fandm.edu 2019-12-10

# Franklin & Marshall – Privacy Notice for F&M Website

This notice explains how F&M will collect and process your personal data when you access this website.

#### 1\. Automated Collection of Personal Information

When you access the College’s website, certain information will automatically be recorded by F&M’s third party website hosting company, Linode, which is managed by our third-party website software vendor, P’unk Ave.  Information collected includes your IP address, what browser you are using and information related to the pages you visit. This information informs decisions about future site improvements and in some instances could aid detection in the event of a security breach.

#### 2\. Non-Automated Collection

Where you are required under this website to provide personal data, the uses of this data will be indicated at the point of collection, for example when filling out an online form requesting more information or to sign up for a College event.

#### 3\. Third-party access

The personal data you provide will only be sent to third parties with which Franklin & Marshall College has a contractual relationship and that 3rd party assists in one or more aspects of the College’s data processing for business purposes.

##### Disclosures

Your data is held confidentially and securely in all of these systems.  These partners are only allowed to use your data in in accordance with the strict instructions of F&M.  Neither party will use your data in any other way nor will they share it with any other organization.

F&M revises this notice annually.  To learn of any changes to these exceptions since the publication date (seen at the bottom of the notice), contact [dpo@fandm.edu](mailto:dpo@fandm.edu)

##### Area #1 - online admissions-related inquiries and applications

F&M, similar to all U.S.-based institutions of higher education works with third party partners (the Coalition for Access, Technolutions, The Common Application, FrontRush, Hobbson’s, RaiseMe, CHEGG and The College Board) as part of our admissions processes.  These partners assist with some or all of the following: identifying potential applicants, processing admissions inquiries, tour scheduling, email marketing and application processing for both Admissions and Financial Aid. Should you be offered admission to F&M, a 3rd-party payment processor will process your credit card deposit payment.

If you submit data through any of the online forms related to admission on F&M’s website, our partner organizations will use your personal data to respond to your inquiry and/or process your application.  You will be asked to acknowledge our intent to collect and process your data in each of these online forms.

##### Area #2- online engagement with alumni and friends of the College

F&M works with a third party partner (iModules) to provide an alumni portal, process online gifts, send email communications and accept online event registrations.  If you submit data through any of the online forms related to alumni, our partner organization will use your personal data to respond to your inquiry and/or process your gift or registration.  

##### Area #3 - to provide better student and employee experiences

F&M works with several third party providers (TerraDotta, HandShake, Blackboard, Maxient, Instructure, OCLC’s WorldShare Management System, FrontRush, ATS, ScriptSafe, National Student Clearinghouse, Interfolio and Interview Exchange, and Rave Mobile Tracker) to provide services to students and in some cases employees as well.  These vendors provide services such as a study abroad application portal, career services and mentoring portal, ID card and dining plan management, athletic team membership management, conduct management, online course management, library lending, academic transcript production, faculty and staff recruitment and hiring support and emergency notification systems.  

#### 4\. Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your device by websites that you visit.

Our website, [www.fandm.edu](http://www.fandm.edu/), uses cookies for three purposes:

  1. To assure the website is functioning properly.  These cookies are set by our webserver

  2. To gather anonymous information about the use of our website so we can continuously improve the site

  3. To capture users’ subjects of interest and then serve targeted advertising on other websites

We do not use cookies to collect personal information about you.

Should you wish to restrict or block cookies which are set by our website, F&M recommends you visit [aboutcookies.org ](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)which contains documentation for a range of browsers.  Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact the functionality of our website.

F&M revises this notice annually.  To learn of any changes since the publication date (seen at the bottom of the notice), contact [dpo@fandm.edu](mailto:dpo@fandm.edu)

##### The table below explains the cookies we use and why:

**Cookie**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---  
  
fandm.sid

| 

**Session ID**

This cookie stores a unique ID assigned by the web server.  It is used to enable some site functionality to work properly.  It is deleted when you close your browser.  
  
_node

_hash

TS01e84c7d

| 

**www.fandm.edu/admission**

These cookies are used by F&M’s apply.fandm.edu  portion of F&M’s website to collect information about how visitors use our site.  We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. These cookies are also used to track users’ interests and then provide targeted advertising on other sites.  The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visit.  
  
_utma

_utmc

_utmv

_ga

_gid

| 

**Google analytics**

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site.  We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. These cookies are also used to track users’ interests and then provide targeted advertising on other sites.  The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visit.  
  
#### 5\. Online advertising

Parts of our website carry a tracking code. This code tracks the page(s) you have visited on the College’s site and passes this to certain other sites you may visit to inform targeted advertising.  This data is anonymous and the College cannot see your name, phone number, email address or any other personal information which could identify you.

#### 6\. Email marketing

Admission, Athletics, Advancement and general Communications email marketing to prospective students as well as parents and alumni may include UTM codes. A UTM code is a simple code that you can attach to a custom URL in order to track a source, medium, and campaign name. This enables Google Analytics to tell F&M which particular marketing message brought you to our website. All email marketing provides an opportunity for you to completely unsubscribe from all F&M-related emails or only from select marketing campaigns.

#### 7\. For more information

Please refer to F&M’s privacy policy for additional information.

For additional information or to make an inquiry regarding F&M’s privacy practices, please contact F&M’s Data Protection Officer.

F&M’s Vice President & CIO, Carrie Rampp, is the College’s Data Protection Officer.    
Franklin & Marshall College  
415 Harrisburg Ave.  
Lancaster, PA 17603  
dpo@fandm.edu

##### Changes to privacy notice

This notice may be reviewed and revised at any time.  

\-------------------------  
Notice Maintained by: Information Technology Services, Vice President and Chief Information Officer  
Last Reviewed: 03 September 2019
